The Little Prince by Antoine de Sonic
superi
this recording is brought to you by our
website if you want to read this story
online or download its PDF file please
visit our website learn English
hyphenew.com
chapter one
hat
the book says snakes eat the whole
animal and they sleep for six months
I think about the life in the forest I
make my first picture this is my picture
number one
I show my fantastic picture to one
person and I ask this person are you
scared
this person answers how can I be scared
it is a hat
my picture is not a picture of a hat
it is a picture of a big snake an
elephant is inside the snake then I make
my picture number two
the picture shows the inside of the big
snake now people understand this is my
picture number two
people tell me what they think they tell
me that it is not good to make pictures
they tell me that it is better to study
a geography history maths and grammar
after these words I don't want to make
pictures I don't want to make pictures
because my picture number one and
picture number two are not good for the
people
people don't understand simple things
and now I am not a child I am a big
person I have a job I am a pilot
I fly planes
I fly in many countries
and it is true that geography is good
for me
geography can help me if I am lost in
the night
in my life I work with people every day
the people are often serious
sometimes I meet a person who is a
little normal
when I meet this person I show him my
picture number one
I always have this picture with me
I want to know if this person
understands life
but the person always says it is a hat
then I never speak to this person about
big snakes or Foresters or stars and we
speak about work Sport and family
and the person is happy for him I am a
normal man
I live alone I don't know people for an
open conversation but one day it all
changed I have an accident in the Sahara
Desert
something is broken in my plane
I have nobody in the plane with me it is
not easy to repair the plane alone
but I must do it it is a question of
life or death I have water for only a
week
chapter two
cheap
the first night I sleep on the sand I am
a thousand miles from a land with people
I think that no people are around me
so I am shocked when somebody speaks to
me in the morning
I hear these words
please draw me a sheep
what
draw me a sheep
I jump up I look around and I see a
little man
this is the picture of the little man
my picture is not very good the original
model is better it's not my mistake I
know how to draw only two pictures they
are pictures of a snake from the outside
and a snake from the inside
I look at this little man
I am really surprised
don't forget that I'm a thousand miles
from a land with people
something is very interesting
this little man is not tired he is not
hungry he's not thirsty he is not scared
he doesn't look lost in the middle of
the desert a thousand miles from a land
with people
the little man says very slowly please
draw me a sheep
it is all very strange to me I'm a
thousand miles from a land with people I
am in danger of death but I take a pen
and paper for my pocket
I want to draw a picture then I remember
that I know only geography history maths
and grammar
and I tell the little men that I don't
know how to draw
he says it is okay draw me a sheep
but I don't know how to draw a shape so
I draw him a picture which I am able to
draw it is a big snake from the outside
and I am shocked when the little man
says no I don't want an elephant inside
a big snake a big snake is a very
dangerous animal and an elephant is very
big for me where I live everything is
very small I need a sheep draw me a
sheep
so I make this picture
the little man's looks at the picture
then he says no this ship is ill make me
another shape
I draw another picture
my friend Smiles at me you must see too
this is not a sheep it is a ram it has
horns
so I make another picture
but this picture also isn't good
this ship is old I want a shape which
can live a long time
it is not easy for me I don't have time
for this I must start my work on the
plane so I draw this picture
and I say this is a box the Sheep is
inside
I am surprised when I see the light in
his face
this is what I want do you think that
this sheep needs a lot of grass
why
because where I live everything is very
small
I think that there is enough grass for
the Sheep this is a very small shape
the little man looks at the picture and
he says
the Sheep is not very small it is a very
nice shape
this is my first day with a little
prince
chapter 3
planet
I want to know more about the Little
Prince I want to know where he lives The
Little Prince asks me many questions I
also ask him questions but he doesn't
answer my questions but when he speaks I
slowly start to understand many things
for example when he looks at my plane he
asks what is the thing I answer it is a
plane it can fly it is my plane
and I am happy when I tell him that I
can fly then he says what are you from
the sky yes I say it is funny
and the Little Prince starts to laugh
I am angry my situation is not good how
can somebody think that it is funny
then he says so you also come from the
sky like me what is your planet
at this moment I start to understand
more about him I ask do you come from
another planet
but he doesn't answer he looks at my
plane again then he says on this thing
you can come from very far
and he starts to think then he takes the
picture with his shape and he looks at
his cheek
but I want to know more so I ask again
where is your planet where do you want
to take your sheep
he is quiet
then he says
the box is a good thing at night I can
use the box as a house for the Sheep
yes and I can also give you a rope then
you can tie the Sheep during the day
but a little prince is shocked when I
say this
tie this sheet it is a funny idea
but if you don't tie the shape the sheep
can run away you can lose the shape
The Little Prince starts to laugh again
but where can the Sheep go
it can go to many places it can go left
it can go right
the little princess the sheep can go
away on my planet it is okay where I
live everything is so small
he's a little sad then he says where I
live nobody can go very far
now I know a second important thing the
planet of The Little Prince is very
small it is like a house
but it isn't really a big surprise I
know that we don't have only big planets
like Earth Mars or Jupiter we also have
hundreds of other planets these planets
are sometimes very small if you want to
see these planets you need a very good
telescope
when an astronomer discovers such a
planet it doesn't give the planet a name
he gives the planet only a number the
name of the planet is for example
asteroid 3251
chapter 4 asteroid
I think that the planet of The Little
Prince is asteroid base 612.
in 1909 one astronomer discovers this
asteroid the astronomer is from Turkey
he speaks about his asteroid at a B
conference but nobody believes him
because he has Turkish clothes it is
crazy but people do these things
but there is something good for asteroid
being 612. a Turkish leader says that
people in Turkey must have clothes like
Europeans
the astronomer speaks about his asteroid
again in 1920. he has very nice clothes
and now everybody believes him
I speak about as Droid
b612 and I speak about its number
because people like numbers when you
tell people that you have a new friend
they never ask you questions about
important things they never ask you is
his voice nice what games does he play
does he have butterflies at home
they ask how old is he how many brothers
does he have how big is he how much
money does his father have
if they know these numbers they think
that they know this person
say to the people I know a small red
house it has beautiful flowers in the
windows a lot of birds fly around the
house
the people can't imagine the house you
must say to the people I know a big
house it is very expensive you can buy
this house for one hundred thousand
dollars
then the people say it is a nice house
if you say to the people The Little
Prince exists because he laughs and he
wants a sheep this information is not
enough for the adults they don't believe
you they think that you live in a dream
but if you tell them the planet of The
Little Prince is asteroid be 612 they
believe you this is how the people think
if you understand life you don't need
numbers you need to hear a nice story
you like to hear The Little Prince lives
on a small planet the planet is very
small The Little Prince is alone he
wants to have a friend
if you understand life this is what you
want to hear
chapter 5
elephants
it is six years after my meeting with a
little prince when I think about him I
am sad but I write about The Little
Prince because I don't want to forget
him it is sad when you forget a friend
not everybody has a friend
this is the reason why I have paper and
colors in my hands now it is difficult
to draw for me when I am old but I want
to do it
I want to make my pictures very good but
I'm not sure if I can do it one picture
is okay but another picture is not very
good
I make some mistakes in the size too
here The Little Prince is very big here
he is very small maybe the color of his
clothes is not correct but I try to draw
as well as possible
but sometimes when my picture is not
perfect it is not my mistake it is The
Little Prince mistake he never explains
things for me maybe he thinks that I am
like him but unfortunately I don't see
the Sheep In The Box
every day new information about The
Little Prince planet comes I also know
more and more about his journey to the
Earth
the information comes very slowly the
information comes during moments when
The Little Prince thinks about his past
for example on the third day The Little
Prince speaks about a problem with the
baobabs baobabs are Big Trees the
conversation about Baobab starts when
The Little Prince asks me a question
about the Sheep
is it true that sheep eat little Trace
yes it is true it is good
I don't understand why it is so
important that sheep eat little trees
but the little princess so they also eat
baobabs
I tell the little prince that baobabs
aren't little trees the baobabs are Big
Trees the baobabs are very big they are
like houses and for example if you put
nine big elephants on your planet these
elephants can eat one Baobab the baobabs
are so big
the idea of nine elephants is funny for
The Little Prince and he laughs on my
planet elephants must stand on elephants
but then he says something clever
when the payo perhaps are young they are
very small
it is true I say but why is it important
that your sheep eats the little baobabs
he says it is simple think about it it
is not very difficult
so I start to think about the problems
with baobabs soon I have the answer
chapter 6.
trees
I think that on The Little Prince Planet
there are good plants and bad plans
it is normal for all planets and of
course there are also good seeds of good
plants and Bad Seeds of bad plants but
we can see seeds they are in the ground
but one day every seed wakes up then the
seed starts to grow the seed grows
slowly to the Sun
when the plant is very small you don't
know if the plant is some vegetable or a
rose
and you can let the plant grow but when
you see that it is a bad plant it is
important to destroy the plant fast
it is true that there are bad seeds on
the planet of The Little Prince
they are the seeds of baobabs
the ground of the planet is full of them
if you see a Baobab too late you can't
destroy it
then The Baobab grows over the whole
planet
and if the planet is too small two or
three baobabs can destroy the planet
this is a question of discipline
The Little Prince tells me
when I wash my face in the morning and
when I put on my clothes that it is time
to clean my planet
it is necessary to pull the baobabs when
I see them
sometimes it isn't easy because they are
similar to roses when they are very
young it is a very boring job but very
easy
in one day he says to me
you can draw a beautiful picture the
picture can show the situation to
Children this information can help
children when they travel around the
universe
in life it is sometimes okay to do your
work later but when you do your work
with baobabs later it is always a big
problem
I know a planet with a lazy man now he
has a big problem he has three big
baobabs on his planet
he is not happy
and when The Little Prince speaks about
the planet I make a picture of this
planet
people know only a little about the
problem with baobabs and it is possible
that one day when you are lost on an
asteroid you can have this problem too I
believe that it is important to know
that baobabs can be very dangerous for a
small planet
I worked so hard on this picture because
I want to tell children about the
problem which they don't know
I also make the picture very big it is
Big because the problem with baobabs can
be very big
chapter 7
Sun
step by step I start to understand the
secrets of The Little Prince life
for a long time his only fun is to watch
beautiful sunsets
this information comes on the first day
in the morning
the little princess
I really like sunsets let's look at a
sunset now
but we must wait I say
wait wait for what
wait for the moment when the sun is down
The Little Prince is very surprised then
he laughs
and he says
I'm always thinking that I'm at home
everybody knows this when it is known in
the United States the Sun is going down
in France if you can fly to France in
one minute you can watch the sunset
but a little prince planet is very small
you only need to pull your chair for or
five mirrors
and you can watch the sunset when you
want
The Little Prince tells me about a day
with 43 sunsets he says when you are
very sad sunsets are great
the day with 43 sunsets must be a sad
day
is it true
I ask
but a little prince doesn't answer
on the fifth day new information about
The Little Prince life comes he asks me
if a sheep eats little trees
but does it eat flowers too
a sheep eats everything what is green
I answer
does a sheep eat flowers with thorns too
yes the Sheep eats flowers with thorns
too
I don't understand
says The Little Prince
why does the flower have thorns if a
sheep can eat the flower
I don't know at that moment I am very
busy I need to repair my plane I am
scared because my situation starts to be
very serious
I have so little water I think that my
death is close
why does the flower have thorns
The Little Prince always wants an answer
to his questions
but at that moment I'm angry because I
can't repair my plane
I answer without thinking
Thorns are good for nothing flowers have
thorns because they want to hurt others
oh
The Little Prince is thinking for a
moment I see that he is a little angry
then he says
I don't believe you flowers are weak the
Thorns give them power flowers believe
that their Thorns are big weapons
I say nothing I am very busy with my
plane
chapter 8. flower
I'm still repairing my plane when The
Little Prince says do you really believe
that lovers have thorns because they
want to hurt others
no I don't believe it but I don't want
to think about it I am busy with my
plane it is a serious thing
he's shocked
serious thing
he looks at me my hands are touching the
engine
the engine is dirty my hands are dirty
too
The Little Prince doesn't like the
engine but engine is important for me
you talk like the adults
The Little Prince is not happy I know
that it is my mistake I don't feel okay
but a little prince continues
you mix everything together
The Little Prince is angry
I know a planet with a gentleman with a
red face he doesn't have a flower he
doesn't look at stars he doesn't love
other people he only counts numbers and
all day he repeats again and again like
you I am a serious man I'm a serious man
and he's very proud but he's not a man
he's a mushroom
he's a what a mushroom
The Little Prince is now very angry his
face is white
flowers have thorns sheep eat flowers
and you think that it is not good to try
to understand why lovers have thorns
there is a war between the sheep and the
flowers and you think that it is not
important
The Little Prince is still very angry he
continues
you think that the water between the
sheep and flowers is not more important
than the numbers of the gentleman with a
rare face
I know a flower which is the only flower
in the world which exists only on my
planet it is a flower which a little
sheep can eat for breakfast and you
think that this is not important
his face is now red he continues
if you love a flower which is in the sky
then you are happy when you look at the
stars you are happy because you know
that your flower is he says up there but
if the Sheep eats the flower then the
sky is very sad for you
he can't say another word
he starts to cry the Night Comes I put
my tools on the ground
how important are my tools my engine my
death now on what planet on my planet
the Earth there is a little prince who
needs me I take him in my arms I hold
him I say to him the flower which you
love is not in danger I can draw you
something which can protect your flower
I can draw you a fence you can put the
fence around your flower I can
I don't know what to say to him
I don't feel comfortable
I don't know how to talk to him how to
be his friend again it is so strange
when somebody cries
chapter 9
class
I soon have more information about the
flower
on The Little Prince Planet the flowers
are always very simple they are small
and they don't talk
they grow in the grass in the morning
and they are gone in the evening
but it all changed one day
there is a different seat it comes from
some place which nobody knows
soon a new flower starts to grow
first she's very small The Little Prince
watched her very carefully
the flower isn't like other flowers on
his planet
the flower can be a new type of Baobab
but she's not a Baobab she is really a
flower
soon she starts to prepare for opening
the appropriation for this moment is
long
the flower doesn't want to show her
colors first
then one morning exactly at Sunrise the
flower shows her colors
and after all her preparation for this
moment she says
ah I am sorry give me some time I need
some time to be perfect
but a little praise can't hide his
feelings
oh how beautiful you are
yes I am beautiful look at me
the flower says
and I am born at the same moment as the
sun
I think that it is time for breakfast
she says
can you bring me some water
The Little Prince is surprised the
situation is new for him but he brings
water to the flower
if lover starts to play with a little
prince
her play isn't always nice
one day for example when she speaks
about her fourth Thorns she says to The
Little Prince
I'm ready for tigers
they can come
there are no tigers on my planet
says The Little Prince
and tigers don't eat grass
I am not a grass the flower says I am
not scared of tigers but I am scared of
wind do you have something which can
protect me from wind
it is not good when a flower is scared
away says The Little Prince and he
thinks this flower is very complicated
at night I want to be under glass it is
very cold here where you live the cold
is not comfortable I come from a place
where
that she stops at this moment
flowers grow from seeds they don't know
about other worlds the flower feels
stupid now
she knows that The Little Prince says
that she can lie to him
she quickly coughs two or three times
she wants to show The Little Prince that
she's cold and that he doesn't care
about her well
the glass
I can look for the glass but you still
talk to me says The Little Prince
then the flower starts to cough a little
more
she wants to show him how bad he is
The Little Prince has a lot of love in
his heart but he can't believe the
flower
for The Little Prince it is important
how somebody speaks to him and the
flower doesn't speak to him well
chapter 10
volcanoes
it isn't good to listen to the flower
The Little Prince tells me one day
never listen to flowers you have to only
look at them and smell them my flower
makes my Planet beautiful she smells so
good but I don't know how to like her
the story about The Tigress makes me so
angry
but it isn't good to take it so
seriously it is good to love the flower
because she is so beautiful and she
smells so good
he then continues
when we are young we don't know many
things the flower makes my Planet
beautiful
it isn't correct to live her
now I know it
I believe that when The Little Prince
lives his Planet wild birds help him
on the morning of his departure he
prepares everything
he cleans his active volcanoes there are
two active volcanoes on his planet
they are very good when he needs to cook
his breakfast in the morning
he also has one volcano which is
inactive
but he says you never know
so he cleans his volcano too
if the volcanoes are correctly cleaned
there are no eruptions of course on
Earth people are very small they can't
clean volcanoes and because people don't
clean them the volcanoes can be a big
problem
before his departure The Little Prince
also pulls the lost little little bail
baths he thinks that this is his last
day on his planet
he doesn't plan to come back
he gives water to his flower
then he brings the glass at that moment
he wants to cry
goodbye
he says to the flower
but she doesn't answer him
goodbye
he says again
the flower cuffs but it is not because
she is ill
I am sometimes stupid the flower says I
am sorry
The Little Prince is surprised that the
father is sorry he doesn't understand
why the flower is nice to him
of course I love you
the flower tells him
maybe you don't feel that I love you it
is not your mistake it is my mistake it
is not important now but you are
sometimes stupid too
try to be happy don't put the class on
me
I don't need it
but the wind the wind is not a problem
the night air is good for me I'm a
flubber
but animals I have to be stronger than
two or three cater pillars if I want to
see the butterflies I think that they're
very beautiful if there are no
butterflies here who can visit me when
you are so far and I'm not scared of big
animals I have my Thorns
and she shows all of her fourth horns to
The Little Prince
then she says
don't stand here you want to leave so go
she says it because she doesn't want to
show her tears
she's a very proud flower
chapter 11.
King
The Little Prince is close to the
asteroids
329 and 330. so he visits these
asteroids first he wants to be busy he
wants to learn something there is a king
on the first planet the King has nice
clothes he is sitting on a big chair
ah here's a visitor the king says when
he sees The Little Prince
and a little prince thinks how can he
know who I am he doesn't know me
come closer to me I want to see you
better says the king he is very proud
that he is a king for somebody now
The Little Prince looks around he needs
a place where he can sit down but the
king's clothes are on the whole planet
so The Little Prince is standing
and because he's tired he owns
it is not good to yawn before a king the
king tells him you can't do it
I can't stop it says the little prince
my journey is very long and I am tired
then you have to yawn says the king
people usually don't yawn before me it
is very interesting yawn again
The Little Prince wants to yawn for the
king but he can't do it now he says I am
sorry I can't yawn when you tell me to
do it says The Little Prince
the king is not happy because people
must do what the king says but because
he's a very good man what he wants is
reasonable
can I sit down
The Little Prince asks
I order you to say down the king says
and he pulls a piece of his clothes so
that there is some space where the
Little Prince can sit down
The Little Prince is thinking about one
thing the planet is very small the king
doesn't control much
can I ask you a question
says The Little Prince
I order you to ask me a question the
king says
what do you control
I control everything says the king
everything
the king looks at his Planet then he
looks at the other planets and all the
stars
are you the king of all asks The Little
Prince
I am the king of all says the king he
doesn't control only his Planet he is
the king of all the universe
and do the starts do what you want
of course says the king
they do it fast they do exactly what I
want
chapter 12.
Mouse
the king's power is very interesting for
The Little Prince
with such power The Little Prince can
watch many sunsets every day not only 44
but 72 or 100 or 200 on the same day
and he can still sit in one place
at that moment he remembers his little
planet and he feels a little sad he asks
the king for something
I want to see a sunset please can you
order the sun to go down
if I order a general to fly from one
flower to another like a butterfly or to
write a book or to change into a seabird
and if the general doesn't do it is it
his mistake
asks the king
your mistake says The Little Prince
exactly you must ask what others can do
the king continues
control has to be reasonable if you
order your people to jump into the sea
they can start a revolution I can
control because my control is reasonable
and my sunset
says the little prince who never forgets
a question when he asks it
you can have your Sunset I can order it
but I have my rules we must wait you can
have your Sunset when the conditions are
right
The Little Prince doesn't want to wait
when are the conditions right for my
sunset
The Little Prince asks
wait
says the king then he takes a big
calendar
this evening at 7 40. and you can see
that everything is as I order
The Little Prince yance he is said that
the conditions aren't right for his
sunset
then this planet starts to be boring for
him
I have nothing to do here
he says to the king
I want to continue on my journey
don't go
says the king he's happy because finally
he is a king for somebody
don't go you can be my minister
minister of what Ministry of Justice
but there's nobody here who I can judge
you never know
says the king maybe there is somebody
here who we don't see
but I can see all your planet
says The Little Prince
he looks at the planet again
there's nobody else on the planet
you can judge you says the king it is
very difficult it is more difficult than
to judge other people if you can do it
it is because you are really a clever
man
but if I want to judge me I don't have
to be here says The Little Prince I can
do it in other places too
I believe
says the king that somewhere on my
planet there is a mouse I hear the mouse
at night you can judge the mouse you can
send the mouse to prison
I don't want to send the mouse to prison
now I think that I can live
no says the king The Little Prince is
ready for his departure but he doesn't
want to make the Old King sad
so he says
if you want to control me you can give
me a reasonable order
for example you can tell me to leave now
I think that the conditions are right
the king says nothing The Little Prince
waits for a moment then he doesn't want
to wait longer and he starts to live
you are my Ambassador the king shouts
adults are very strange
The Little Prince thinks when he
continues on his journey
chapter 13.
people
The Little Prince comes to the second
planet he sees another strange man
the man likes when people admire him
another person who admires me says the
man when he sees The Little Prince
he believes that all people admire him
good morning says The Little Prince
you have a funny hat
I used his hat when I say good morning
to people who come to visit me but not
many people visit me here
really
says The Little Prince really clap your
hands says the men The Little Prince
claps his hands and the man touched his
hat and he moves the Hat a little
this is more fun than the visit to the
king
The Little Prince thinks
The Little Prince claps his hands again
and again the man touched his hat again
and again
after five minutes of this exercise The
Little Prince starts to be tired of this
game
do you only touch your head or can you
do something else
he asks but the man doesn't hear him
this type of people never hear other
people they hear only when somebody
admires them
do you really admire me very much
he asks The Little Prince
what is admire
to admire is to believe that I am the
most handsome the richest and the most
intelligent man on the planet
you are the only man on your planet yes
I know that I am the only man on this
planet but please admire me
I admire you says The Little Prince but
I don't understand why it is so
important to you
The Little Prince has nothing else to do
on this planet
so he continues on his journey
adults are very strange he thinks when
he is living this planet
when a little prince visits the next
planet he sees a man this man drinks a
lot
he is drunk
this is a very short visit and it is a
sad visit
what are you doing
he asks the drunk man
the drunk man sits before bottles
some bottles are empty some bottles are
full
I am drinking says the drunk man
his face is not happy
why are you drinking
The Little Prince asks
I want to forget
says the drunk man
to forget what
asks The Little Prince
to forget that I feel horrible
says the drunk man and he puts his head
down
why do you feel horrible
asks The Little Prince
The Little Prince wants to help the
drunk man
I feel horrible because I drink so much
I know that it is bad to drink so much
says drunk man then he is quiet
The Little Prince leaves the planet
adults are very very strange he thinks
when he continues on his journey
chapter 14 businessman
The Little Prince visits the fourth
planet
there is a businessman on this planet
he is very busy he is so busy that he
doesn't look at The Little Prince When
The Little Prince comes
good morning says The Little Prince
your secret is finished
three and two make five five and seven
make twelve twelve and three make
fifteen oh hello fifteen and seven make
twenty two twenty two and six make
Twenty Eight I have no time to light the
secret again 26 and 5 make 31 it has 501
million six hundred and twenty two
thousand seven hundred and Thirty One
500 million what asks The Little Prince
are you still here 501 million oh I
don't remember I have so much work to do
I'm a serious man I don't want to lose
my time with things which are not
important two and five make seven
500 million what
repeats The Little Prince
he wants the answer to his question
the businessman looks at The Little
Prince
I am 54 years old I don't like when
somebody stops my work it doesn't happen
often I remember only three times the
first time 22 years ago a bird falls on
my table the birds makes a horrible
sound and I make four mistakes in my
calculation
the second time 11 years ago I have for
through medicine I don't have enough
exercise I don't have enough time for
such activity I'm a serious man
the third time is now where am I
501 million
million what
the businessman understands that if he
wants to have peace he has to answer his
question
millions of those little things which
you sometimes see in the sky
flies no not flies Bees No the little
golden things lazy people like them
because they can dream when they look at
them but I am a serious man I have no
time to dream
Stars yes the Stars
and what do you do with 500 million
stars
500 Min 1 million
731 I'm a serious person I need numbers
which are correct
and what do you do with those Stars
nothing I own them
you own the Stars
yes
but I know a king who Kings don't own
they control it is very different
and why is it good to own Stars
when I own Stars I am rich
and why is it good to be rich
when I'm rich then I can buy more stars
if somebody discovers them
but how can you own the Stars it is
simple who owns them
asks the businessman
I don't know nobody
then I own them because I am the first
person who has this idea
is it enough
of course when you find a diamond it is
your diamond when you discover an island
it is your Island when you have a new
idea your patent is and it is your idea
now I own the stars because I am the
first person who has this idea
it is true says the little man
The Little Prince
and what do you do with them
I look at them I count them and I count
them again
says the businessman
it's difficult but I'm a serious man
The Little Prince wants to know more
if I own a jacket I can put the chicken
on me and I can take it with me
if I own a flower I can pick the flower
and take the flower with me but you
can't pick the Stars
no but I can keep them in the bank
how can you do it
it is easy I write the number of my
stars on a little paper and then I put
the paper in the back
and it is enough it is enough
says the businessman
it is funny thanks The Little Prince
but it is not very serious
the little princess to the businessman
I own a flower I give her water every
day I own three volcanoes I cleaned
volcanoes every week
I also cleaned the volcano which isn't
active you never know it is good for my
volcanoes it is good for my flower that
I own her I help my flower and I held my
volcanoes but you don't help the Stars
the businessman opens his mouth and he
can't find words
and a little prince lives
the adults are very interesting he
thinks when he continues on his journey
chapter 15.
lamp
the fifth planet is very interesting it
is a very small planet there is only a
limp and a limp lighter on the planet
The Little Prince doesn't understand why
there is a lamp and a lamp lighter on
the planet
there is enough light because the planet
is under many stars there are no other
people on the planet who need a lamp
The Little Prince thinks
this man is strange but he is less
strange than the king the businessman or
the drunk man
his work makes the world more beautiful
when he turns on his lamp it is like a
new star in the sky or new Flubber when
he turns off his lamp he sends the
flower or the star to sleep
it is a beautiful job and because it is
beautiful it is a good job
when The Little Prince comes on the
planet he says to The Lamplighter good
morning why do you turn on and turn off
your lamp
it is an order
says the limp lighter and he turns off
the lamp
what is the order
the order is to turn on and turn off my
lamp
good evening
and he turns on his lamp again
why do you do it so often
it is the order
says the limp lighter
I don't understand
says The Little Prince
it is simple says the lump lighter the
order is the order
good morning
and he turns off his lamp
then he says
it is a terrible job now I remember
better days in the past I turned off the
lamp in the morning in the evening I
turn on the lamp again
I have all the day for me and at night I
can sleep
and is the order different now
the order is the same
says the limp lighter
it is the problem year by year the
planet is turning faster and faster and
the order is still the same
now the planet turns around every minute
and I have no time to sleep I turn on
and I turn off my lamp every minute
it is funny your day is only one minute
long
it is not funny
says bluntlighter
our conversation is already one month
long
a month yes 30 minutes 30 days good
evening
and he turns on his lamp again
The Little Prince watched The
Lamplighter he likes more and more this
man who follows the order
he wants to help his new friend
I can show you how you can stop your
work
I always want to stop my work
says The Lamplighter
The Little Prince continues
your planet is so small that you can
walk around in it three long steps you
only have to walk more slowly and you
can always be in the Sun
when you want to stop your work only
walk and you never have to work again
how can this help me set as the lump
lighter
the one thing which I love in life is to
sleep
then you are not lucky says The Little
Prince
I am not lucky
says Lamplighter good morning
and he turns off his lamp
The Little Prince continues on his
journey he thinks the other man the king
the drunk man the businessman can laugh
at this Lamplighter but he is better
than the other man it is because he
cares about something else not only his
things this man can be my friend but
this planet is too small there is no
place for two people
The Little Prince doesn't want to say
the real reason why he doesn't want to
leave his Planet he doesn't want to
leave because the planet has
1440 sunsets every 24 hours
chapter 16. geographer
the sixth planet is bigger than the last
planet
the little princess an Old Gentleman
the man writes big books
oh here comes an explorer
he says when he sees The Little Prince
The Little Prince sits down on the table
he is tired from traveling so long and
so far
where are you from
the Old Gentleman asks him
what is this big book
asks The Little Prince what are you
doing here
I am a geographer the Old Gentleman
answers
what is a geographer
a geographer is somebody who knows where
the seeds are and rivers cities
mountains and deserts
it is very interesting
says The Little Prince
finally here's a man who has a real job
he thinks and he looks around at the
geographer's planet
your planet is very beautiful
he says does this planet have oceans
I can say
s the geographer
ah The Little Prince is sad
and mountains
I can say
s the geographer
ncts and rivers and deserts
I can't tell you says the geographer
but you are a geographer
it is true says geographer but I am an
explorer there is no Explorer on my
planet the drugver doesn't Discover
cities rivers mountains Seas oceans and
deserts
the geographer doesn't have time for
traveling
he doesn't live his office but the
Explorer visits his office he asks them
questions and he writes what they
remember
and if the information is interesting to
him then the geographer has to ask more
questions about the Explorer he has to
know if the Explorer is a good person
The Little Prince wants to know why the
Explorer has to be a good person
the geographer says
an explorer who is a bad person can give
information which is not correct and
also an explorer who drinks very much
can give bad information
why
asks The Little Prince
because drunk people don't see correctly
then the geographer can draw two
mountains in a place where there is only
one
I know somebody
says The Little Prince
who drinks a lot he can be a bad
Explorer
it is possible so when the Explorer is a
good person then I have to check if his
information is correct
do you visit the place
no it is too complicated but Explorer
has to give me proof for example if he
knows about a big mountain the Explorer
has to bring some Stone from the
mountain
then jog for smiles
but you come from very far you are an
Explorer you must tell me about your
planet
the geographer opens his big book
he prepares his pen
tell me about your home
says the geographer
oh where I live
says The Little Prince
it is not very interesting it is very
small I have three volcanoes two
volcanoes are active and all volcano is
then active but but you never know
you never know
says geographer
I also have a flower
we don't write about flowers
says the geographer
why not the flower is the most beautiful
thing on my planet
because Flowers don't live very long in
geography we have very correct books our
books are almost always true a mountain
usually doesn't change its position an
ocean usually doesn't lose its water
we write about things which are here for
a long time
but volcanoes which aren't active can be
active again
says The Little Prince
the volcanoes are active or not it is
the same for us
says the geographer a volcano is a
mountain it is important a mountain
doesn't change your flower is different
your flower can be gone soon
my flowery can be gone soon
of course
my flower can be gone soon
thanks The Little Prince
and she has only four Thorns for
protection and she is home alone
The Little Prince is sad but he wants to
continue on his journey
what is an interesting place to visit
he asks
the planet Earth
the geographer answers
it is a nice planet
and your little prince continues on his
way
he is still thinking about his flower
chapter 17.
Earth
the seventh planet is the Earth
the Earth is a very big planet
there are a 111 Kings on Earth
there are also 7 000 geographers 900
000 businessmen
seven and a half million drunk man
311 million men who need to be admired
together 2 billion adults live on this
planet
the Earth is really big
I want to show you how the big planet is
I want to give you one example
for electricity
511 lamplighters work on Earth
these slump lighters have to turn on and
turn off the lamps on six continents
when you look at the Earth from some
distance you can see a beautiful show
the lead lighters are like the dancers
in the Oprah their organization is
perfect
the lamplighters of New Zealand and
Australia come first
they turn on their lamps then the
lamplighters of China come then the
lamplighters of Russia and India then
the lamplighters of Africa and Europe
then the lamplighters of South America
and of North America
and they never make a mistake
it is beautiful
only the limp lighter of one lamp at the
North Pole and his colic at the South
Pole have easy lifts they work twice a
year
when I speak about the limp lighters you
can think that there are many people on
earth
now I want to tell you more about people
on earth
people take very little space on Earth
if the 2 billion people on earth stand
close together
they can all be in one square
the square is 20 miles long and 20 miles
wide
you can put all people on a small island
of course adults don't believe this
information
they think that they take a lot of space
they think that they are as important as
the baobabs
but they can make their own calculation
they love numbers and they like to count
but you don't have to do it it is not
necessary believe me
when The Little Prince comes on Earth
he is surprised
he is surprised because he doesn't see
any people
he starts to think that he is on the
wrong planet
but then he sees something in the sand
good evening
says Little Prince
says the snake
what is this planet
asks The Little Prince it is the planet
Earth you are in Africa says the snake
oh are there no people on earth
this is the desert there are no people
in the desert
says the snake The Little Prince sits
down on a rock he looks at the stars
look at my Planet the little princess
my planet is up there
but it is very far
it is beautiful
the snake says
why are you here
I have some problems with a flower
says The Little Prince
ah
says the snake in he is quiet
chapter 18.
Garden
where are the people
The Little Prince continues in the
conversation with a snake after some
time
I feel alone in the desert
you feel alone with people too
says the snake
The Little Prince looks at him for a
long time
you are a funny animal
he says
you are very slim
the snake says I am slain but I am
stronger than a king
The Little Prince smiles
you are not very strong
you don't have legs you can't travel
very far
I can take you very far
the snake says
he turns around The Little Prince leg
when I touch somebody I can send the
person back to the land from which he
comes the snake says
but you are a good person and you come
from a star
the snake continues
you are so weak on this planet I can
help you one day if you want to go back
to your planet
I can bite you and you can travel very
far
oh
I understand
says The Little Prince
The Little Prince says goodbye to the
snake then he is walking in the desert
he meets a flower
good morning says The Little Prince
good morning
says the flower
where are the people
The Little Prince asks
people
I believe that six or seven people live
on earth I see them sometimes in a
caravan but you never know where they
are the life is very difficult for them
because they don't have any Roots the
wind takes them away
Goodbye Says The Little Prince
Goodbye Says the flower
The Little Prince sees a high mountain
the only mountains which he knows are
three volcanoes which are as high as his
knees
he thinks
from this high mountain I can see the
whole planet and all the people
he goes to the top of the mountain but
he only sees other mountains around
hello
he says
hello hello hello
the ego answers
who are you
asks The Little Prince who are you who
are you who are you
the echo monsters
let's be friends I am alone
he says
I am alone I'm alone I'm alone
the ego answers
this is a strange planet
he thinks the planet is dry and hard and
people here only repeat what you say to
them
on my planet I have a flower
she always speaks first
The Little Prince is walking for a long
time through sand and rocks
then he finally sees a road
and all roads go to people
good morning says The Little Prince
he is standing before a garden full of
roses
good morning
say the Roses
The Little Prince is looking at the
Roses
they all look like his father
he is surprised
how are you he asks
we are roses
the Roses say
ah says The Little Prince
and he is very unhappy his flower says
that she is the only flower of her kind
in the whole universe
and here are 5 000 roses all the same in
one Garden
he thinks
so my rose is not very special
I have only a normal Rose so I have a
normal Rose and three volcanoes which
are as high as my knees
it isn't much I think that I am not a
great Prince
and he is lying in the grass and he is
very sad
chapter 19.
Fox
then the fox counts
good morning
says the fox
the little princess
who are you
you are very pretty
I am a fox
says the fox
play with me the little princess
I am very sad
I can't play with you I am Wild
the fox says
ah I am sorry
says The Little Prince
but after some time he asks
what is wild
you are not from here says the fox
what are you looking for
I'm looking for people
says The Little Prince
what is wild
people
says the fox
have guns they hunt it is a problem for
me
they also have chickens I like chickens
are you looking for chicken
no says The Little Prince
I am looking for friends
what is wild
when I am wild I am not connected to you
and you are not connected to me
you are not connected to me
it is true the fox says
for me you are only a little boy like
other little boys
and I don't need you and you don't need
me for you I'm only a fox like other
foxes
but if I'm not wild for you you need me
and I need you you can be the only boy
in the world for me I can be the only
fox in the world for you
I start to understand
the little princess
I have a flower
I think that she isn't wild for me
it is a possible says the fox
on Earth we can see many different
things
oh my flower is not on Earth
the little princess
the fox asks
on another planet
yes
are there Hunters on your planet
no
it is interesting and chickens
oh nothing is perfect
says the fox
after some time the fox says
my life is always the same
I hunt chickens men hunt me all the
chickens are similar and all the men are
similar to
so it is a little boring
my life can be better if I am not wild
for you
when I hear your steps I can be happy
the other steps can scare me
but your steps are like music to me and
it is not old
do you see the cornfields there
I don't eat bread
for me corn is not important the
cornfield say nothing to me and it is
sad
but you have golden hair
your hair is beautiful
the corn is also golden when I see the
corn I remember you
when I hear the wind in the corn I can
be happy
the box is quiet
the fox looks at The Little Prince for a
long time
please stay with me for some days
the fox says
it can be nice to stay with you
says The Little Prince
but I don't have much time
I want to find friends I want to learn
new things
we only learn about things which are
connected to us
says the fox
people don't have time to learn
they buy things from shops
but because there are no shops where you
can buy friends
people don't have friends
if you want a friend be connected to me
okay
what do I have to do
asks The Little Prince
you have to be very passionate
says the fox
first you have to help me not to be wild
you have to sit at a little distance
from me in the grass
I can watch you with one eye and you say
nothing
words can be a problem sometimes but
every day you can see it a Little Closer
chapter 20
Secret
the next day The Little Prince returns
it is better if you return at the same
hour
says the fox
if you come for example at four in the
afternoon then at three I start to be
happy
at 3 30 I am more happy it for I am very
I can show you how happy I am
but if you come a different time I don't
know when I can start to be happy
we need some rules
why do we need rules
asks The Little Prince
the rules are important
they make one day different from other
days their rules make one hour different
from other hours
for example Hunters have their rules too
they dance with the girls from the
village every Thursday so Thursday is a
beautiful day I can walk to the village
with no problems
if the hunter stands on different days
I don't know when it is holiday for me
[Music]
so The Little Prince spends some time
with the fox every day and when the hour
of his departure is near the fox says
ah I'm sad I want to cry
it is your mistake says The Little
Prince
I don't want to hurt you
but you want to be with me
yes of course
says the fox
but you cry
says The Little Prince
yes of course
says the fox
but then you get nothing
I get something
says the fox
the color of the Corn helps me get
something
then the fox says
go and look again at the Roses
you can understand now that your rose is
special
then come back to say goodbye to me I
have a present for you the present is
Secret
The Little Prince goes to look at the
Roses again
he speaks to them
you are not like my rose
the little princess
you are nothing to me at this moment
nobody's connected to you and you are
connected to nobody
you are like my fox on the first day not
connected to me
but the fox is my friend now
and the fox is special to me
then he continues
you are beautiful but you are empty
nobody wants to die for you
of course if somebody only walks around
my rose my rose is not special to this
person
but my rose is more important to me than
all the other roses because she is Rose
who I give water
she is the Rose who I put under the
glass
she is my rose
I listened to her when she is not happy
and I listened to her when she is happy
The Little Prince returns to the fox
goodbye
he says
says the fox
here is my secret it is a simple secret
you see clearly only with the heart
what is important eyes can't see
repeats The Little Prince
he wants to remember this Secret
the time which you spend with your rose
makes your rose so important
the time which I spent with my rose
makes my rose so important
says The Little Prince
people forget one truth
says the fox
but this truth is important
you are responsible for something what
is connected to you
you are responsible for your roles
I am responsible for my rose
the letter Prince repeats
chapter 21.
trains
good morning says The Little Prince
good morning
says the man who works at the railway
station
what do you do here
The Little Prince asks
I changed the direction of the trains
says the men
I sent some trains to the right ain't
some trains to the left
and at that moment a train goes around
very fast
they hurry says The Little Prince
what are they you're looking for
nobody knows what they are looking for
says the man
and a second train goes around in the
opposite direction
are they going back
asks The Little Prince
they are not the same people
says the man
they are different people
they are coming back
they are not happy where they are
people are never happy where they are
says the man
and a third train goes around
do they want to catch the first people
asks The Little Prince
they don't want to catch anybody
says the men they are sleepy or they're
looking outside the windows
only the children are pressing their
noses against the windows
only the children know what they are
looking for
says The Little Prince
children use their time to play with
toys
and the toys start to be very important
to them
and if somebody takes their toys they
cry
children are lucky
the man says
The Little Prince continues on his
journey
good morning
says The Little Prince when he meets a
businessman
good morning
says the businessman
he's a businessman who sells peels
the peels help people when they are
thirsty
if you take one pill a week you don't
have to drink
why do you sell the peels
asks The Little Prince
because the pills save a lot of time
says the businessman
the appeals can save 53 minutes a week
and what do you do with the 53 minutes
what I want
when I have 53 minutes
the little princess
I like to walk very slowly to a fountain
chapter 22.
desert
it is now the eighth say after my
accident in the desert I listen to the
story about the businessman and I am
drinking my last water
your stories are very nice
I say to The Little Prince
but my plane is still broken I have
nothing to drink
I also want to walk very slowly to a
fountain
my friend the fox says that my dear
little man this has nothing to do with
the fox
why not
because soon I am dead
but a little princess it is good to have
a friend and if he can die soon it is
good to have a friend too I am very
happy that I have a fox as a friend
he doesn't see the danger
I think
he's never hungry or thirsty he only
needs a little sunshine
but he looks at me and maybe he knows
what I am thinking because he says
I am thirsty too
let's look for a well
it is crazy to look for a well in this
big desert but we can start to walk
we walk for many hours then the Night
Comes the Stars start to shine I see
them as in a dream
I am very thirsty the last words of The
Little Prince dance in my head
so you are thirsty too
I asked him
but he doesn't answer my question
he only says to me
water can also be good for the heart
I don't understand his answer but I say
nothing I already know that he doesn't
answer my questions he is tired he sits
down
I sit down next to him
after a quiet moment The Little Prince
speaks again
the stars are beautiful because there's
a flower on one of them
sure I say then I look at the scent
the scent is all around us
we see the sand in the light of the Moon
the desert is beautiful
it is true I always love the desert when
I sit down on sand in the desert I see
nothing I hear nothing but something
beats and something shines in the desert
chapter 23
well
the desert is beautiful
says The Little Prince
because it hides a well somewhere
I agree with the Little Prince
when I am a little boy we live in an old
house
and people say a story about the house
the story says that the house has a
treasure somewhere in the floor
of course nobody can find a treasure
maybe nobody is really looking for it
but this treasure makes the house
special
my home is hiding a secret
yes
I say to The Little Prince
what is beautiful we can't see
I am happy he says that you agree with
my fox
then The Little Prince starts to sleep
I take him in my arms
I start to walk again
I am full of emotions I'm holding the
Little Prince
I feel that I am holding a great
treasure
in the Moonlight I look at his white
face
his closed eyes his Golden Hair which
Moves In The Wind
and I think
what I see here is only a shell what is
most important we don't see
and when his mouth opens a little with a
smile
I think again
what is so beautiful about this little
prince is his relationship with his
flower I can see a picture of a rose
which shines from his heart when he
sleeps
I feel that I have to protect this light
the wind can take the light away
I continue to walk
and in the morning I see the well
The Little Prince wakes up and he says
people get on their trains but they
don't know what they're looking for
people run around it's not necessary
the well is not like the walls of the
Sahara the wells of the Sahara are only
holes in the sand
the swell looks more like a village well
but there's no Village here and I think
that I am in a dream
it is strange I say to The Little Prince
everything is ready the bucket the Rope
The Little Prince laughs he takes the
rope and he lets the bucket go down the
well
when a bucket is going down we hear some
interesting sound
can you hear it
says The Little Prince
the well is singing
chapter 24.
water
when the bucket is full of water I say I
can pull the bucket up the bucket is
very heavy for you
slowly I pulled the bucket up I leave
the bucket on top of the well
I am tired but happy
the song of the well is still in my ears
when I look at the bucket I can see the
sunshine in the water
I am thirsty
says The Little Prince
I want to drink this water now
I help him hold the bucket he drinks
with his eyes closed it is nice it is a
special moment the water isn't only a
drink the water comes from our walk
Under the Stars
it is made from the song of the Well
from the work of our Arts it is good for
the heart like a present
when I am a little boy I like Christmas
very much it is a special time
I like the light of the Christmas tree
the Christmas music the smiles of the
people
all these things make the Christmas time
and Christmas presents special
where you live
says The Little Prince the people have 5
000 roses in one Garden
but they don't find what they are
looking for
but what they're looking for they can
find in one rose or in a little water
yes it is true
I say
and a little princess
but the eyes don't say it you have to
look with the heart
I drink a lot of water I feel well now
the sand and sunrise in the color of
honey
and that color is making me happy too
so I don't understand why I feel so sad
do you remember your promise
says The Little Prince when he sits down
next to me
what promise
you know a fence which can protect my
flower from my sheep I am responsible
for this flower
I take my pictures out of my pocket The
Little Prince looks at them he laughs
when he sees the baobabs
your baobabs look like some vegetable
oh
I am very proud of my baobabs
your Fox his ears look like horns and
they're too long
and he laughs again
you are not fair Little Prince
I say
I can't draw I can draw only snakes from
the outside and snakes from the inside
oh it is okay
he says it is okay for children the
children understand
I draw a fence and I give the fans to
The Little Prince with a heavy heart
you have plans which I don't know
maybe something ends here
but he doesn't answer me he says to me
you must work now you must go back to
your plane I can wait here
come back tomorrow
chapter 25.
wall
next to the wall there is an old wall
when I come back from my work the next
evening I see The Little Prince from
some distance
he is sitting on the top of the wall
he is talking to somebody
he says
this is not the right place
some voice must say something to him
because the little princess
yes yes this is the right day but it is
not the right place
I continue my walk to the wall I still
can't see or hear anybody but a little
princess again
sure you can follow my steps in the sand
you only have to follow me to that place
it can all happen tonight
I'm 20 meters from the wall and I still
can't see anything The Little Prince
speaks again after a boss
do you have good poison
are you sure that you can do it very
quickly
I saw my heart is beating strongly
but I still don't understand the
situation
now go away
says The Little Prince I want to go down
from the wall
then I look down at the sand under the
wall
I am shocked
there is a yellow snake there
it is a snake which can kill you in 30
seconds
I want to take my revolver
but when I'm trying to take it
I also make a step back
the snake hears it starts to move and he
is quickly gone in the rocks
I still hear him but I don't see him
I come to the wall
I catch the little prince in my arms
his face is very wide
what are you doing here
I want to know
why are you talking with a snake
he looks at me
his eyes are sad he puts his arms around
my neck
I feel his heart
his heart is beating like the heart of a
bird which is dying
he says to me
I'm happy that your plane is okay now
you can go home
how do you know it
I am here because I want to tell him
that my work is finished
he doesn't answer my question but he
says
I can go back home today too it is very
far I need somebody's help for my next
Journey
chapter 26.
present
I know that something strange is
happening
I am holding the little prince in my
arms like a little child
but I feel that he is falling down into
a big hole and I know that I can't help
him
his face is very serious now
he says
I have the sheep and I have the box for
the Sheep and I have the fans
and he smiles sadly
I wait for a long time
I see that he is feeling a little better
than I say
dear little man you are scared
yes he is scared but he laughs a little
I am scared of tonight
it is difficult for me I know that it is
not possible to change for The Little
Prince wants to do
I can't imagine my life without the
sound of The Little Prince lab
for me it is like a fountain in the
desert
little man
I say
I want to hear you laugh again
but he says to me
tonight it is already a year
my star is exactly in the same place as
last year
my little friend is this only a bad
dream
is the meeting with a snake the plan for
tonight only a bad dream
but he doesn't answer my question
he says to me
what is important we can't see
yes I know
it is the same with the flower
if you have a flower which lives on a
star
it is good to look at the sky at night
then all the stars have flowers
yes I know
at night you can watch the Stars
the little princess
my star is very small I can't show you
where my star is
it is better if you don't know my story
can be one of the many stars for you
so when you look at the stars they can
all be your friends
I have a present for you
says The Little Prince and he laughs
again
ah The Little Prince My Little Prince
I love to hear you laugh
I say
this is my present my laugh
says The Little Prince
chapter 27.
Bells
I am not sure if I understand
I say your laugh is at present
people look at stars but the stars are
not the same for everybody
for people who travel the stars are
guides for other people the stars are
nothing
only small lights in the sky
for scientists they are problems for my
businessman the stars are important
because they make him rich but all these
stars are quiet Stars
for you it is different
you have stars like nobody else
when you look at the sky at night
there's one star where I live and
because I laugh on one of these Stars
you can feel that all stars are laughing
you have stars which laugh
and he laughs again
when I live
The Little Prince continues
you can be sad
but believe me time can help you be less
sad
then you can be happy that you know me
you can always be my friend you can
always laugh with me
and sometimes you can open your window
only for fun and your friends can see
you how you laugh at the sky
you can tell them yes the Stars always
make me laugh and your friends can think
that you are crazy but it is okay
and he laughs again
and for you the Stars can be like little
bells which laugh
and he laughs again
then he's serious again
tonight don't stay with me
I don't want to leave you
I say
tonight it can look as if I feel pain it
can look as if I am dying don't come to
see it it is not necessary
I don't want to leave you
but he says
I also ask you not to come because the
snake can bite you
snakes are bad sometimes
snakes can bite you only for fun
then he says
it is also true that snakes have no
poison for the second bite
then the cons
I don't see The Little Prince leaf I
don't hear him when he goes away from me
when I catch him he is walking fast
he only says to me
ah you are here
and he takes my hand but he is not happy
it is wrong that you are here it is not
good for you
it can look as if I am dead but I am not
that
I am quiet
you must understand my star is too far I
can't take this body with me it is too
heavy
I am quiet
when you see only an empty shell don't
be sad there's nothing sad about empty
shells
I am quiet
he tries to explain it again
he says
this night can be very nice for me all
the stars can be Wells with a rope and a
bucket
all the stars can have water for me
I am quiet
it is great fun you can have 500 million
little bells and I can have 500 million
fountains
and he is quiet too
but he is crying
chapter 28.
departure
here is the place let me continue alone
says The Little Prince
and he sits down because he is scared
then he says
my flower is on my planet I am
responsible for her and she is so weak
she has only four Thorns which can't
protect her enough
I sit down too because I can't stand
it is all
he says
he waits for some time
then he stands up he takes one step
I can't mow
I see something yellow which moves
quickly near his leg
he doesn't move for a moment
he doesn't cry
then he falls slowly as a tree falls
now it is six years after the Little
Prince departure
this is the first time when I tell the
story
when I return the people are happy when
they see me
I am sad because the Little Prince is
gone
but I say to the people that I am not
sad that I am only tired
now I am not so sad I know that the
Little Prince is on his Planet because I
don't find his body at sunrise
and at night I love to listen to the
Stars
it is like 500 million little bells
but here is something interesting the
fence for the Sheep is not very big
so sometimes I think
what is happening on his Planet if the
Sheep jumps over the fence the sheep can
eat the flower
but sometimes I think of course not The
Little Prince puts his flower under the
glass every night and he wants his sheep
well
then I am happy
and all the stars laugh a little
sometimes I think
everybody can forget sometimes
everybody can forget to put the glass
over the flower in the evening
and the sheep can come to the flower in
the night in
then the bells change to tears
for some people it is not important
for you who also love The Little Prince
and for me these things are important
so look up at the sky and ask the
question
is the flower still on The Little Prince
Planet and can you can see how
everything changed
and adults can never understand that
this is so important
for me this is a very beautiful and also
very sad land
I want to make another picture of this
land
it is the same as the picture before
but I want to draw the land again
I want to remember the land better
it is the land where I say goodbye to
The Little Prince
look at this picture carefully
because you can come to this planet one
day when you travel in Africa in the
desert and if you really come to this
place
don't hurry
wait for a little moment
then if a little man comes if he laughs
if he has golden hair and he doesn't
answer your questions you know who he is
if this happens please write to me
quickly that The Little Prince is back
foreign
[Music]